*當我們共舞時*
*When we dance together*
*我的世界變得虛幻*
*My world's in disguise*
*猶如童話*
*It's a fairyland tale*
*終于成真*
*That's come true*
*你看著我*
*And when you look at me*
*眸中有星空*
*With those stars in your eyes*
*我愿與你跳著華爾茲穿越德州*
*I could waltz across Texas with you*
*跳著華爾茲穿越德州*
*Waltz across Texas*
*懷里抱著你*
*With you in my arms*
抱歉出了點小問題  馬上就能修好
Sorry about the hiccup, folks. It won't be long.
*和你跳著華爾茲穿越德州*
*Waltz across Texas with you *
*像童話里的結局*
*Like a storybook ending*
*我被你深深吸引*
*I'm lost in your charms*
給你五分鐘
You got five minutes.
*我愿與你跳著華爾茲穿越德州*
*And I could waltz across Texas with you*
大家好
Howdy, folks.
請問阿爾瑪·梅·厄爾巴諾女士在車上嗎
Could someone tell me if Mrs. Alma May Urbano is on board?
阿爾瑪·梅·厄爾巴諾
Alma May Urbano.
你在這兒  你好親愛的
There you are. Hello, dear.
真高興認識你
Very good to meet you.
我叫吉米
My name's Jimmy.
之前在磯鷂渡時我想拜訪你
I tried to visit you at Sandpiper,
但他們不讓
but they wouldn't allow me to.
你知道嗎
Hey, you know what?
那也沒關系
It doesn't matter.
我看見車壞了  你正好在車里
I saw your bus broken down, here you are.
我真幸運
Lucky me.
你希望我稱呼你厄爾巴諾女士
Do you prefer to be called Mrs. Urbano
阿爾瑪·梅  還是只叫阿爾瑪就好
or Alma May or just plain Alma?
我姓麥吉爾  但叫我吉米就好
My last name is McGill, but you can call me Jimmy.
大家好  我叫吉米·麥吉爾
Hey, everyone! My name's Jimmy McGill.
我是名律師  但別在意我
I'm an attorney at law, but, uh, don't mind me.
你們繼續聊天吧
Just talk amongst yourselves.
阿爾瑪·梅
Now, Alma May,
你還記得回復過我律所寄來的信函嗎
do you recall responding to a mailer from my law firm,
新墨西哥州圣達菲的戴維斯梅因律所
Davis & Main, of Santa Fe, New Mexico?
我記不住了
I...I don't know.
我們想幫助那些
Well, we were looking to help any Sandpiper residents
因基礎商品和服務
who may have been overcharged
可能被超額收費的磯鷂渡居民
for, uh, basic goods and services.
這回能想起來了吧
Now, does that ring a bell?
可能吧  是黃色的信封嗎
Maybe. Was it yellow?
是淺黃色的
It's canary yellow.
我親自選的那種顏色
I picked that color myself.
女士  我來這兒是為了確保你能拿回那筆錢
Well, ma'am, I'm here to make sure you get your money back.
你們在說什么
What are you talking about?
誰奪走了阿爾瑪·梅的錢
Who took Alma May's money?
這個問題問得好
Uh, well, now, that's a very good question.
感謝你的提問  你是
And thank you for asking, mister, uh...?
艾莫斯  艾莫斯·萊德克
Amos -- Amos Lydecker.
萊德克先生  我是吉米·麥吉爾
Mr. Lydecker, Jimmy McGill.
其實不是誰搶走了誰的錢
Now, nobody took anybody's money, uh, exactly.
明白嗎
Okay?
不是磯鷂渡的人
It's not like the Sandpiper people, you know,
戴上滑雪面罩
put on a ski mask and, uh...
持槍打劫了阿爾瑪·梅
mugged Alma May here at gunpoint.
你們別在腦中想象這種場面
So I want you to put that mental image right out of your head.
我們現在說的更像是一種
See, what we're talking about here is more of a --
一點小矛盾
it's just a discrepancy.
一件小事而已
It's -- it's a little thing.
沒什么惡意
It's -- it's fairly innocent.
但我們得解決
But we need to fix it.
明白嗎
Do you follow me?
這么說吧
Well, put it this way.
阿爾瑪·梅  假設說你和你男朋友
Alma May, let's say you're out on a date
出門約會
with your boyfriend.
你有男朋友  是吧
You do have a boyfriend, right?
沒有嗎
You don't?
拜托  你
Come on. You --
阿爾瑪·梅瞞著我
Alma May's holding out on me.
你有侄子嗎
Do you have a nephew?
侄子嗎  有  他叫史蒂夫
Nephew? Oh, y-yes -- Steve.
好  史蒂夫
Okay, Steve.
他是個好人嗎
Is he a good guy?
他非常好
Yeah, very good.
好
Okay.
假設說你和史蒂夫
So, let's say you and Steve go out to dinner
去博蒂餐廳吃飯
at, uh... well, Birdie's.
-你們今天都要去那兒  是吧  -對
- That's where you're all headed today, right? - Right.
好
All right.
你們倆享受了一頓大餐
So, both of you have a great meal.
你們吃了軟炸牛排配青豆
It's chicken-fried steak and green beans,
一切都非常完美
and it's all perfect.
該結賬了
Here comes the check.
"等一下
"Hey, wait a doggone --
"一塊奶酪餅干竟然要二十四塊錢
24 bucks for a side of buttermilk biscuits?
"這可不太對勁  是吧"
That doesn't sound right, now, does it?"
當然不對
No, it does not.
似乎是算錯了
It sounds like something got added up wrong.
你當然要派你侄子史蒂夫
Well, naturally, you send your nephew Steve
去和經理談談
to talk to the manager,
經理當然也改正了錯誤
and naturally, the manager corrects the mistake.
而且  他還送給你一張
And what's more, he gives you a coupon
下次免費吃飯的優惠券
for a free meal next time you come in.
這聽起來怎么樣
How about that?
很好
Good.
如今  磯鷂渡也是這么一回事
Well, same kind of thing is what happened at Sandpiper Crossing.
最令我心痛的莫過于
And nothing makes me sadder
眼見美國最偉大的一代
than to see people of the Greatest Generation --
經歷了經濟大蕭條  參與了二次世界大戰的一代
我自己爺爺奶奶那一代
people like my own Nana and Bobo --
被一些大公司敲竹杠
gettin' overcharged by some great, big company --
就算那純屬意外
even if it was an accident.
我知道磯鷂渡的好伙計們
Now, I know that the good people at Sandpiper
遲早都會改正錯誤  但你知道嗎
want to make this right sooner or later, but you know what?
有時候呢  把事交給侄子史蒂夫
Well, sometimes, it's just easier if you get your nephew Steve
你會更輕松
to go take care of it for you.
而你可以把我當成他
And that's how I want you to think of me.
喬治亞娜
Georgiana.
喬治妹妹  謝謝你
Hey, there, Georgie girl. Thank you.
我需要的都在這兒了
Oh, it's all there, everything I need.
非常感謝你們  好好享用午餐
Thank you so much. Enjoy your lunch.
阿爾瑪·梅  真棒
Alma May, you did it.
謝謝你  謝謝你
Thank you so much. Thank you.
謝謝  亨利
Thank you, Henry.
博蒂餐廳
很好
All right.
你好  蘇  很好
Hey, Sue. Okay.
優美的字跡
Beautiful penmanship.
失傳的藝術
A lost art.
絕命律師
第二季 第三集
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗  TheWalkingNerd  酸奶
斯韋卡特和考科利正考慮采取主動攻擊策略
Schweikart and Cokely are pursuing an aggressive strategy,
但參考相關判例法
but looking at the relevant case law,
我認為這位地方法官不會吃這一套
I don't think it's going to play with this magistrate judge.
翻譯  joy_bwl  肉松  西陵折枝  自然卷
我研讀了她許多過去的判決
I read over a dozen of her rulings,
所有類似案件中  她都站在原告這一方
all of which have sided with the plaintiff on cases like this.
校對  喃喃
我已將此作為備忘附在今天的資料里
I've included a memo to that effect in today's materials,
時間軸  喃喃  姜姜  念念
供各位空暇時細讀
which you can peruse at your leisure.
謝謝  艾琳
Thanks, Erin.
我們接著討論客戶聯系事宜吧
How about we move on to client outreach?
后期  四月追番的小新     總監  喃喃
吉米
Jimmy?
你在聽嗎
You still with us?
我來說吧  免得你自夸
I'm gonna save you from having to brag.
過去三周內有超過兩百位磯鷂渡新委托人簽字
Over 200 new Sandpiper clients signed over the past three weeks.
做得好  吉米
Well-done, Jimmy.
謝謝你  謝謝  克利福德
Thank you. Thanks, Cliff.
目前
Uh, right now,
我們正在整個西南地區尋找委托人
we're in the process of mapping out the entire southwest,
優先鎖定幾家最大的磯鷂渡機構
targeting the largest Sandpiper facilities first.
鳳凰城  科泉市  沃思堡  普羅沃
Phoenix, Colorado Springs, Fort Worth, Provo --
這還只是第一步
that's just for starters.
我的理想目標是  月底前再簽下兩百人
Ideally, my goal -- another 200 by the end of the month.
有了這么多人  我們有很大機會
With this many folks, we have an excellent shot
在各區的集體訴訟中
at a solid batch of plaintiffs
積累足夠的原告人數
for the classes in each district.
非常好
Excellent.
期待你下一次匯報
Look forward to the next report.
接著是更棘手的議題  協調訴訟
On to a stickier wicket -- coordinating actions.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
繼續討論之前
Before we move on,
我想再花點時間談談客戶聯系
I'd like to go back to client outreach just for a moment.
看到這些數據
Looking over these numbers here,
成果真是驚人  吉米
really, astonishing results, Jimmy.
真了不起
Incredible.
你這一趟阿馬里洛之行
Your last trip to Amarillo,
帶回了二十二個新委托人
you came back with 22 new clients.
-是二十四  -二十四
- 24. - 24.
我有點疑惑
I'm confused.
總共有多少人回復了我們的直達信函
Um, how many people out there actually responded to our direct mailer?
一個
One.
是的  好的
Oh. Right. Yeah.
阿爾瑪·梅·厄爾巴諾太太
A Mrs. Alma May Urbano.
但你從一個回復里又搞定了二十四位新委托人
But you got 24 new clients from this one response?
這真是...
That is -- Wow.
過獎了
Well, you're welcome.
怎么  難道有問題嗎
I mean, what? Is there a problem?
這難免會讓某些人
Well, uh, might not some parties --
比方說  辯護方
the opposing counsel, for example --
發現這差異  因此認為
see this differential and conclude
這其中可能存在教唆之嫌
that there may have been some solicitation involved?
我沒有教唆他們
I did not solicit.
我只想知道你如何解釋你的成功
I'm just wondering how you account for your success.
因為這必定會引起
Because it will definitely raise eyebrows
斯韋卡特和考科利的質疑
over at Schweikart & Cokely.
抱歉但這是事實
I'm sorry, but it will.
特別是牽涉到老年人的案子
Particularly in a case involving seniors,
美國律師協會有關教唆的職業道德規范
for whom the ethical guidelines on solicitation
實際上就是為老年人而制定的
were virtually created by the ABA.
查克  我確定...
Chuck, I'm sure that --
吉米  如果你能解釋明白
Jimmy, if you could clear this up,
會大有幫助
that would be helpful.
我去了阿馬里洛探訪一位客戶
I went to Amarillo to confer with a client
確保我們在當地的案子
and to make sure that we had a solid,
建立在真誠可靠的基礎上
good-faith basis for our case there, overall.
如你們所知
And as many of you are aware,
我拜訪了比計劃多得多的養老院
I've visited more than my share of retirement homes.
他們可是關系緊密的社群
These are close-knit communities.
消息傳播得總是特別快
Let me tell you, word gets around real fast.
住二期的桃樂茜買了輛新的電動車
If Dorothy in Phase Two gets a new Rascal Scooter,
馬上大家就知道了
well, it's big news.
所以其他二十三位老年人主動找到你
So these other 23 residents, they approached you.
克利福德  在我踏進德州前
Cliff, they heard the scuttlebutt
他們早已聽到了風聲
before I crossed state lines.
我更沒有必要挨家挨戶拜訪
And I certainly didn't have to go knocking on any doors.
他們都很想和一位帶來好消息
And is it any surprise that they want to speak
說他們有錢拿的人談話
with the guy who was there to show them
這有什么好驚訝的嗎
they may have money coming their way?
我得說  這么一想
I gotta tell you, with all that in mind,
我還可以做得更好
I should've done better.
有道理  霍華德
Makes sense. Howard?
查克
Chuck?
我們能繼續了嗎
We good to move on?
查克這也不是順帶一提
And, Chuck, not incidentally,
這至關重要
it is absolutely vital
我們必須十分謹慎
that we dot our I's and cross our T's here.
謝謝你寶貴的意見
Invaluable. So, thank you.
完美的代價乃永恒的警惕
The price of excellence is eternal vigilance.
沒錯
Indeed.
協調
Coordination.
我們剛剛是談到這里吧
I believe that's where we left off.
沒錯
That's right.
布萊恩  你負責這個  你來說吧
Brian, this is your thing, so why don't you take this?
好吧
Sure.
考慮到這些案子所涉及的方面
Considering the dimensions of these cases,
進行具體分析和綜合考量后
taken together and individually,
應該指定專人進行規劃安排
it makes sense to designate someone to handle the scheduling.
我建議在戴維斯梅因成立一個小組
What I'm proposing is that we create a small team at D&M
專門負責協調單個訴訟及其之間的
dedicated specifically to coordinating all elements
所有因素
of the individual actions.
我們凡事都會告知哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
We'll loop in HHM on anything --
布萊恩  抱歉
Uh, Brian, I'm sorry.
抱歉打斷你一下
Excuse me for interrupting.
我只是想說我同意查克的觀點
Uh, I just want to say that I take Chuck's point.
真的
I do.
意即不能接受別人的懷疑
就像凱撒之妻一樣
I mean, this is, like, a wife-of-Caesar type of thing.
連教唆的意思都不能有
There can't even be a hint of solicitation.
所以我準備不這么辦了
So I'm gonna pull back.
好吧  不到磯鷂渡搞什么見面會了
All right, no more meet-and-greets at the Sandpiper facilities.
我會另想辦法的
I'll find another way to proceed.
吉米  這我們就交給你了
Well, Jimmy, we'll leave that up to you.
聯系客戶是你負責的事
You know, client outreach is your department.
說到哪兒了來著
Uh, where was I?
對
Okay, right.
如果我們能在新墨西哥有更穩固的指揮中心
If we have a more consolidated nerve center here in New Mexico,
就能...
where the...
金  我該上哪兒搞尼德曼的供詞
Hey, Kim, uh, where can I get a copy of that Neiderman deposition?
我有一份多的  吉米
I've got an extra Neiderman, Jimmy.
給你一份吧
You can have one of mine.
謝了  艾琳
Oh, wow. Thanks, Erin.
不客氣
Yeah, no worries.
該死  我放哪兒了
Shoot. Where'd I put that?
謝了...
Thanks, that's...
查克真是令人難以置信
Man, do you believe Chuck in there?
天啊  還教唆
Jesus. Solicitation?
我告訴你  我們當初拼命立案的時候
Let me tell you, when we were building this case,
我可是追在逛商場的八十歲老頭后面
I was chasing down 80-year-old mall walkers.
這才叫教唆
That was solicitation.
但他有說我什么嗎
But did he say "Boo"?
當然沒有
Bullshit he did.
在德州發生了什么
What happened in Texas?
沒什么
Nothing.
我做了我該做的
I did my job.
你沒有在休息室里給那些老家伙載歌載舞嗎
You didn't do a song and dance in the dayroom for the old-timers?
沒有  沒有
No. No.
沒...沒在休息室里
Not -- not in the dayroom.
吉米  你知道教唆他人會讓你被取消律師資格的
Jimmy, you know solicitation can get you disbarred.
這很重要
This matters.
我認為最重要的是
Well, here's what I think matters --
現在二十四名老年人有自己的代表了
24 senior citizens now have representation.
我去之前
Before I went,
他們根本不知道自己被剝削了
they didn't even know they were getting ripped off.
現在他們有我們撐腰
Now they have us in their corner.
這怎么能不算一種勝利呢
How is that not a win?
你剛剛說你會另想辦法
You said in there you'd find another way.
你是認真的嗎
Did you mean it?
當然了  絕對的  我...
Sure. Absolutely. I --
聽著  我...
Look, I...
我要告訴你一件非常重要的事
I need you to understand something very critical here.
說吧
Shoot.
為了給你弄到這份工作  我拿我的飯碗作擔保
I put myself on the line to get you this job.
好吧
Uh, okay.
我還以為是因為我擅長與老人打交道呢
I thought it was 'cause I'm sensational with old people.
那你以為是誰告訴他們的
Yeah, and who do you think told them that?
所以呢...這算是你幫了我嗎
So, what -- you threw me a bone?
不...混蛋
No...asshole.
你知道我相信你
You know I believe in you.
后來我也說服他們相信你
But then I made my beliefs known to them.
現在你做的一切在霍華德看來就代表著我
And now everything you do reflects back on me with Howard,
因為說到底  是我說服他
'cause ultimately, I talked him into
冒險讓你試一試
going out on a limb for you, too.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
是...是我的承諾  是我的判斷
It's -- it's -- it's my word, it's my judgment.
明白
Yeah.
你我都知道你能勝任這份工作
You and I both know you can do this job.
但拜托你用正確的方式
But please, you just have to do it right.
你得確保
Well... you want to make sure
電池的方向正確  不然沒有用
you put in the batteries the right way or he won't work.
然后合上蓋子
Then you close them up.
然后...
And...
我覺得...我覺得這樣就行了  小姑娘
I think -- I think you're good to go, young lady.
你捏一下它的腳試試
Why don't you give his foot a squeeze?
它真好笑
He's funny!
親愛的
Oh, darlin'.
我就叫你...哼哼先生吧
I think I'll name you... Mr. Snuggles.
你餓了嗎
Are you hungry?
我去給你拿點土豆泥
I'm gonna get you some mashed potatoes.
這些錢應該夠你撐過下個月了
That should get you through to next month.
麥克  謝謝
Mike, thank you.
但你其實沒必要...
But you shouldn't feel that you need to --
太遲了
Too late.
出什么事了
Something up?
感覺好像有什么事
Feels like something's up.
不  只是...
No, it's...
我睡得不夠
I didn't get much sleep.
-我的頭...  -抱歉
- My head's... - I'm sorry.
跟我說這不關我的事  那我就不管了
You tell me it's none of my business, I'll drop it.
我不想讓你擔心
I don't want you to worry.
我也不喜歡擔心
Not the worrying kind.
前兩晚  我聽到了槍聲
Last two nights, I heard gunshots.
第一晚  可能在一兩個街區外
First night, they were maybe a block or two over
我驚醒了
and woke me up.
我第一反應是鞭炮聲
My first thought was firecrackers,
我當時這么認為的
and that's what I assumed at the time,
但是昨晚  我絕對沒聽錯
but then last night -- there's no mistaking it.
一共三聲
There was three of them.
很快  "啪啪啪"三聲  更近了
They were quick -- pop, pop, pop -- closer.
好像...
It was...
他們就在房子外面
like they were right outside the house.
你報警了嗎
You call the cops?
報了
Yeah.
警察一小時后才過來
Took them over an hour to get here,
在周圍看了整整兩分鐘
then they looked around for a whole two minutes,
當然沒什么發現
but by then, of course, there was nothing to see.
我今晚待這兒
I'm staying here tonight.
不用  麥克
No, Mike, no.
-沒這個必要  -我沒問題
- That's not necessary. - No, it is not a problem.
我睡沙發
I'll take the couch.
麥克  你問了我才回答
Mike, you asked, so...I answered.
別讓我后悔告訴你
Please don't make me sorry I told you.
凱莉  過來
Kaylee, come, hmm?
吃晚飯
Get your supper.
那科泉市呢
What about Colorado Springs?
283個居住者  發了283封信函
283 residents, and we sent out 283 mailers.
行  那有多少回函呢
Yeah, and how many response cards came back?
零
Zero.
零嗎
Zero?
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
達納  托尼  再見
Dana, Toni, have a good one.
再見  梅因先生
Bye, Mr. Main.
You, too, Mr. Main.
克利福德  能談會兒嗎
Cliff, uh, could I have a second?
怎么了
What's up?
是寄給磯鷂渡信函的事
Uh, yeah, it's the Sandpiper mailers.
我們應該有約百分之十二到十五的回信
Yeah, we should be getting responses of like 12 to 15 percent,
但只有一兩個點
but we're getting ones and twos.
科泉市甚至為零
In Colorado Springs, zero.
怎么會這樣
Wow. How can that be?
他們員工搞的鬼吧
I'm thinking it's the staff.
信封交給居住者前就被員工扔了吧
They're tossing the mailers before they can reach the residents.
可能是他們上級要他們這么做的
Maybe they got told to do it by the Sandpiper front office,
真可以以這個起訴他們
which would be actionable as hell.
前提是我們能證明  但很難做到
If we could prove it. Big "if."
我需要更多人力才做得到
And to do so would take more manpower than I can spare.
我們現在先繼續爭取更多委托人
For now, let's just stick with getting those client numbers up.
你最好另尋他法
Guess you better think of another way.
已經想好了
I think I got it.
電視廣告  更具針對性
TV commercial. Highly targeted.
告訴你  在磯鷂渡里一切都很準時
Let me tell you, at Sandpiper, the trains run on time.
將意大利塑造成整齊劃一和嚴密控制社會的法西斯領袖
墨索里尼會很驕傲
Mussolini would be proud.
我至今拜訪的每個人日程都完全相同
Every one I visited so far, same exact schedule.
上午十點  水中有氧操
10:00 A.M., water aerobics.
下午兩點  隊列舞
2:00 P.M., line dancing.
諸如此類
So on and so forth.
下午三點到四點都是自由活動
They always leave 3:00 P.M. to 4:00 P.M. free.
為什么  因為要看《女作家與謀殺案》[美劇]
Why? "Murder, She Wrote."
這劇長盛不衰
It's been in syndication since like the 1850s,
跟你說  只要電視里一開始演
and let me tell you, when that thing comes on,
那些老年人就像飛蛾撲捕蟲燈一樣
it draws the blue-hairs like moths to a bug zapper.
下午三點十四  第一段以懸念結束后
3:14 P.M., end of the first-act cliffhanger,
進第一個廣告  戴維斯梅因律所
first commercial up, Davis & Main.
保證賺足眼球
Guaranteed eyeballs -- lots of 'em.
磯鷂渡對此無能為力
There's nothing Sandpiper can do about that.
我們幾年前做過一個廣告
We ran a commercial a few years back --
也是起集體訴訟案
another class-action case.
對我們算是新鮮事
Kind of a new thing for us.
我不習慣這么做
Now, it's not exactly my go-to,
但我持開放態度
but generally speaking, I'm open to it.
我們下周再談
We will talk next week.
真棒
Great.
一路平安
Safe travels.
朱利安出品
客戶  戴維斯梅因律所
"間皮瘤"
如果你或你的家人被確診患有
If you or a family member have been diagnosed
間皮瘤或相關疾病
with mesothelioma or related conditions,
你可獲得經濟賠償
you may be entitled to monetary damages.
間皮瘤是一種罕見肺病
Mesothelioma is a rare lung disease,
通常因接觸石棉患病
usually associated with exposure to asbestos,
石棉是已知致癌物
a known human carcinogen.
長期吸入石棉纖維
Long-term inhalation of asbestos fibers
會導致嚴重甚至致死疾病
can cause serious or fatal illnesses,
包括惡性肺癌
including malignant lung cancer,
間皮瘤和石棉肺
mesothelioma, and asbestosis.
我記得他們很努力才弄好那個
Remember they worked real hard to get that just right.
弄好什么
To get what just right?
波紋效果
Oh, the -- the swirl.
他們想做得朦朧些  但又不要太朦朧
They wanted it kind of nebulous, but not too nebulous.
還有速度的問題
Then there was the issue of the speed.
我記得他們為此開了很多會
I remember there were a lot of meetings about that.
...受害者和他們的家人
...victims and their families.
-我想是吧  -免費咨詢
- I'll bet. - For your free consultation,
請撥打戴維斯梅因律所505-242-7700
call Davis & Main at 505-242-7700.
That's 505-242-7700.
克利福德同意拍這玩意兒嗎
Cliff signed off on this?
合伙人非常高興
The partners were very happy.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
我覺得...
I think...
這算哪門子廣告  演技呢
whatever happened to showmanship?
看過來
Yo, check it out.
利口樂
Ricola!
你們兩個混蛋小丑能專業點嗎
Will you two ass clowns act like the professionals
要對得起你們父母為你們花的錢
your parents are paying for you to become?
這東西很貴的
This happens to be very valuable.
是嗎  這是什么
Yeah? What is it?
這個是阿爾卑斯牧童
This one is, uh, the Alpine Shepherd Boy.
送給她侄子的
It's for her nephew.
來  跟我來
So, come -- join me.
制片會議  開始吧
Production meeting -- bring it in.
好
All right.
聽著  團隊合作實現夢想
Now, look, teamwork makes the dream work.
我們同心協力  就能夠
Together, we can make something --
可以這么說  共譜華美樂章
dare I say it? -- bravura.
這是千載難逢的良機
And this is a golden opportunity,
尤其是對你倆來說
especially for you guys,
因為會在整個西南部播出
'cause it's gonna play all around the Southwest,
誰知道這會帶來什么呢
so who knows what it could lead to?
最好能給我們每人帶來一百塊
It better lead to a hundred bucks each.
你要錢做什么
What is it with you and money?
存起來買VX2000攝像機
Saving up for a VX2000.
問你們個問題
Hey, pop quiz --
我們三個與韋爾斯  費里尼和伯格曼
what do we three have in common with the greats --
三人均為著名導演
這樣的偉大人物有什么共同點
Welles, Fellini, Bergman -- the biggies?
什么
What?
他們三人  無一例外
All three of them -- to a man --
都曾在利潤豐厚
worked in the highly lucrative,
憑創意獲取回報的廣告業工作過
creatively rewarding field of advertising,
而今晚  我們就要跟隨他們的腳步
and tonight, we join them.
這讓人興奮  對吧
This is heady stuff, right?
那么  聽好了
Okay. So, pay attention.
畫面從老奶奶開始  她坐在搖椅上搖
We open on granny, and she is rocking.
就這樣來回地搖
So she's back and forth,
慢慢地搖啊搖
just very back...and forth.
然后  非常緩慢且平穩地
And then, very slowly and smoothly,
攝影機移向她的...
the camera, uh... moves towards her...
-移動攝影車嗎  -移動攝影車  沒錯
- Dolly? - A dolly -- good.
你看這有移動攝影車嗎
See a dolly here?
你們沒帶移動攝影車來
You guys didn't bring a dolly?
沒有
Nope, no dolly.
你沒說要帶移動攝影車來
You didn't ask for a dolly.
-得提前說  攝影車要額外收費  -是的
- Gotta ask, dude. Dolly's extra. - It's true.
好吧  那就沒有吧
Okay, no dolly.
那我們就即興發揮一下
We will improvise, then.
順著我的思路
Stay with me.
她搖晃著
She's rocking.
打著寒戰
She's shivering.
緊緊抓著一個破舊的披肩
She's clutching at a tattered shawl.
那些混蛋把她的暖氣停掉了
They turned the heat off on her, these evil bastards.
她又冷又餓  孤單一人
She's cold and hungry, she's friendless.
真是一幅令人心痛的畫面
This is heart-rending stuff, man.
一個長鏡頭  背景用黑白色調
Okay, it's a oner, and it's shot in glorious black and white.
這個可以做到吧
We can do that, right?
可以
Yeah.
就這樣而已嗎
So that's it?
老太太坐在椅子上
Old lady in a chair?
這就是你的廣告
That's your commercial?
你這副樣子有人喜歡嗎
Does anybody like you?
我準備好拍特寫了  麥吉爾先生
I'm ready for my close-up, Mr. McGill.
一記高飛球  稍偏離正中
...And an easy, easy pop fly off dead center.
墨菲在之前的八場比賽中29擊13中
Murphy's gone 13 for 29 over his last 8 games,
安打率為0.343  非常棒
batting a blistering 343 overall,
劉易斯現在又在跟教練商量
and now Lewis again working quickly with the bench.
墨菲投球  球觸地兩次進入人群
Murphy swings, it's a two-hopper into the crowd.
界外球
Foul ball.
祝你今天愉快
Have a good one.
出什么事了
Hey, honey. What's happening?
怎么了
What's wrong?
發生什么了
What happened?
凱莉呢
Where's Kaylee?
她沒事  在學校  她還不知道
She's at school. She's fine. She doesn't know about it.
你還好吧
Are you all right?
我帶你去看看
Let me show you.
那上面
It's up -- it's up there.
你看到了嗎
You see it?
就在那上面
It's right up there.
看到了嗎  你看到它的形狀了嗎
You see that? You see the shape of it?
你看到了吧
You do see it, right?
看到了
I-I see it.
你什么時候聽到的槍聲
What time did you hear the shots?
凌晨兩點十三分
2:13 this morning.
我當時看了鐘  一共有三聲
I looked at the clock. It was three of them.
跟上次一模一樣
It was exactly like last time.
你也沒有報警  報了嗎
And you didn't call the police. Or did you?
沒有  報警有什么用
No, I... What's the point?
我在想有沒有其他的可能...
I'm thinking outside the box, but...
有沒有可能是你做夢夢到的
you think maybe it's possible that you dreamed it?
有時會發生這種情況
It happens sometimes.
我沒有做夢  麥克
I didn't dream it, Mike.
因為我昨晚一夜沒合眼
Because I didn't sleep a wink last night.
這就是子彈的痕跡  肯定是
That came from a bullet. I mean, it must have.
昨晚之前還沒有
It wasn't there before last night.
我跟你保證  我不知道...
I promise you that, and I don't know --
好了
Okay.
-好了  -天啊
- Okay. - Jesus...
我就在這里
I mean, I was here.
我一直在這里  而你不在
I was here, and you weren't.
我相信你
I believe you.
好吧
All right.
那就這樣  你和凱莉要離開這棟房子
That's it. We're getting you and Kaylee out of this house.
就這么定了
End of story.
你對這些東西不好奇嗎
You ever wonder about these things?
什么東西
What things?
這個  為什么會有這些東西
This. Like, what's the story with these?
是誰第一個說
Who was it who first said,
"我知道了  就放一大碗球吧"
"Hey, I know -- big bowl of balls."
我不知道
I don't know.
房子自帶的
They came with the place.
要你說
No shit.
世界上每間公司臨租房里都有這東西
They're in every corporate apartment in the world.
就像基甸國際贈送的《圣經》
They're like the Gideon Bible.
好啦  不要嫉妒我的一大碗球了
Hey, don't be jealous of my big bowl of balls.
別丟人了
It's unbecoming.
為什么一定要擺空花瓶呢
Why do they all have to have empty vases?
法律規定的  這是比喻的說法
Well, it's the law. Plus, it's a metaphor.
我必須得說
I got to say,
我會想念美甲店的振動按摩椅的
I will miss the Nail Salon's vibrating chairs.
為了你
Well, for you,
我可以把這的任何椅子都變成振動椅
I can make any chair in this place vibrate.
準備好了嗎
You ready for this?
好的  開始播放
Kay. Here goes.
你現在八十六歲
You're 86 years old.
是科泉市磯鷂渡生活協助中心的住戶
You're a resident of Sandpiper, Colorado Springs.
你剛剛吃完你的午茶點心  酸橙果凍
You just finished your afternoon snack, lime Jell-O.
酸橙  了解
Lime, got it.
你正在休息室
You're in the dayroom,
看你最愛看的電視劇
you're watching your favorite TV program.
出什么事了呢
What's this?
卡伯特灣又發生了一樁謀殺案嗎
There's been another murder in Cabot Cove?
不會吧
No!
沒錯  警長無能為力
Yes. The sheriff is in over his head,
杰西卡·弗萊徹不得不再次
and once again, Jessica Fletcher has to put aside the novel
把她在寫的小說放一邊來協助執法
she's been writing and assist law enforcement.
令人震驚的是
Shocker!
兇手留下一封密文  然后進廣告
The killer left behind a cryptogram -- and commercial.
新墨西哥大學  媒體實驗室出品
戴維斯梅因律所
《是誰偷走了你的養老金》
我丈夫和我節衣縮食過了很多年
My husband and I scrimped and saved for so many years.
為了不成為家庭的負擔
We did our best to build a nest egg
我們盡力攢下了一筆養老金
so that we wouldn't be a burden to our family.
羅納德去世后  我搬進了一家生活協助中心
After Ronald passed, I moved to an assisted-living facility --
很不錯的地方
a nice place.
他們說會照顧好一切
They told me they'd take care of everything,
但有一天  他們說我一分錢都沒有了
but then, one day, they said all my money was gone.
怎么會這樣
How could that be?
錢都去哪兒了
Where did it all go?
她裝哭的是吧
That's not a real tear, is it?
-如果你或是愛人...  -是眼藥水
- If you or a loved one... - It's Visine.
...是磯鷂渡生活協助中心
...is a resident of a Sandpiper Crossing facility
或是其他有關退休社區的居民
or other associated retirement community,
你也許有資格獲得補償
you may be eligible to receive compensation.
如需免費咨詢
For a free consultation,
請致電戴維斯梅因律所
call the law offices of Davis & Main
電話505-242-7700
at 505-242-7700.
That's 505-242-7700.
怎么樣
Well?
你拍的嗎
You made that?
和一些電影專業學生做的嗎
With... some film students?
我導的
I directed.
看起來  很專業
It looks... professional.
還有呢
And?
如果我是一個八十六歲的磯鷂渡居民
And if I were an 86-year-old Sandpiper resident...
我會打過去
I'd be dialing.
太棒了
Yes.
擊掌
Up top.
而且一切都遵守了
And all made in accordance with the rules and regulations
美國律師協會的規章制度
of the American Bar Association.
很好
Good.
真不敢相信戴維斯梅因會支持你
I can't believe Davis & Main went for it.
那么
Well...
我現在主管客戶聯系
I'm in charge of the department.
是啊  但克利福德居然沒有異議
Yeah, but still, you know, Cliff Main was fine with this.
他為什么會有
Why wouldn't he be?
不  我是說這太棒了
No, it's -- it's fantastic.
慶祝一下吧
Let's celebrate.
我要加點酒  你要嗎
I'm getting more wine. You want some?
還用問
Absolutely.
《戴維斯梅因律所  是誰偷走了你的養老金》
非常好  謝謝
Very good. Thank you.
科羅拉多州科泉市
Colorado Springs, Colorado.
我想要KKTV11頻道的號碼
Yeah, I'd like the number for KKTV, channel 11.
奧馬爾  聯邦快遞什么時候下班
Omar, what's the cutoff for FedEx?
我要寄個包裹  十萬火急
I need to get a package out, tout suite.
是的  能幫我接通你們的廣告銷售部嗎
Uh, yes, can you connect me to your ad sales department?
多謝
Thanks.
牙床沒問題  沒有老化
Gums look good, no recession.
舌頭也沒問題
Tongue looks good, too.
眼睛不渾濁
Eyes are clear.
這個小美女身體很好
This little lady's in fine fettle.
如果需要  我可以叫人修剪一下它的指甲
We can have one of the girls trim her nails, if you like.
不用了  改天吧
No, some other time.
有什么工作嗎
What do you got for me?
保鏢  兩百塊
Bodyguard job, 200 bucks.
還有嗎
What else?
那是我這兒最適合你的了
For you, that's the best fit I've got.
我認識一個放高利貸的
I know a loan shark.
一直需要人去幫他收賬
Always needs enforcement and recovery.
報酬不錯而且穩定
Pays good, and it's steady work.
大多數時間只是放放狠話
Most of the time, we're just talking intimidation, strictly verbal.
"大多數時間"
"Most of the time."
我才不要當打手
I'm not breaking legs.
還有嗎
What else?
聽著  我們討論過
Look, we discussed this.
你想多賺點  就要做相應的工作
You want next-level pay, you got to do next-level work.
我尊重你的原則
I respect where you're coming from on this thing.
真的
I do.
但事情就是這么辦的
But that's just how it goes.
好了
All right.
它要打六個月疫苗
She's gonna need a DHPP shot, six months.
我們會給你發提醒卡的
We'll send you a reminder card.
到時再說吧
Till then.
給我保鏢的工作
Give me the bodyguard job.
兩百塊行嗎
For $200?
時間地點打電話告訴你
Call you with the where and the when.
大家都知道...
So, everybody knows --
都知道了
They know.
所有以7700開頭的電話線路
Every line starting with 7700
都已經轉到等候區還有你的辦公室
has been rerouted to the bullpen, plus your office.
所有助理都會保持線路暢通
All the assistants know to keep them open.
如果你在打電話時另一通電話進來
So, if you're on a call and another call comes in,
電話不會被轉到答錄機對嗎
the call doesn't go to an answering machine, right?
因為  這非常重要
Because -- very important --
老年人不喜歡和機器人說話
old people don't like talking to robots.
如果我在打電話  另一通電話進來
If I'm on a call and another call comes in,
會轉給梅達
it'll roll over to Maida.
然后艾里斯會接下一個
After that, Iris will get the next one,
再然后朱利安  然后芭芭拉
then Julian, and then Barbara,
還有伊馮  一個接一個下去
and Yvonne, right on down the line.
好極了
Good.
那就這樣
Let's make that the plan, then.
所以...
Oh, so --
你的表幾點了
What time do you have?
過一刻了
Uh, quarter after.
廣告應該在播了對吧
It should be running now, right?
還有什么事嗎
Is there... anything else?
沒了  謝謝
No. Thanks.
我會在辦公室的
It's...I'll just... be in my office.
快來電話啊
Come on.
快打快打  科泉市的電話  快來啊
Come on. Come on, Colorado Springs, come on.
下午好  戴維斯梅因律師事務所
Good afternoon, Davis & Main, attorneys at law.
有什么能為您效勞的
How may I help you?
是的  女士  是的  真是太不幸了
Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am, that is unfortunate.
立案需要您先留一下姓名
Now, to get your case started, may I ask for a name
以及電話號碼  方便我們的律師聯系您
and the number for one of our attorneys to reach you?
下午好  戴維斯梅因律師事務所
Good afternoon. Davis & Main, attorneys at law.
有什么能為您效勞的
How can I help you?
是的  沒錯
Yes, that is correct.
下午好  戴維斯梅因律師事務所
Good afternoon, Davis & Main, attorneys at law.
Good afternoon, Davis & Main.
這里是磯鷂渡熱線
Sandpiper hotline.
有什么能為您效勞的
How can I help you?
我們稍后再聯系您
We'll get back to you.
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我們馬上把相關材料寄給您
We'll be happy to send an information packet right out to you.
請問您目前居住在
May I ask, are you currently a resident
磯鷂渡生活協助中心嗎
of a Sandpiper Crossing facility?
下午好  戴維斯梅因律師事務所
Good afternoon. Davis & Main.
Good afternoon. Davis & Main, attorneys at law.
漂亮
Bingo.
什么事
Yeah.
今晚來了一個活
Something came in this evening,
報酬絕對高
and it's definitely next-level pay.
是嗎
Yeah?
不過你這么挑剔  估計又不肯接吧
It's probably a long shot, given your selectivity.
什么活
What's the job?
我問了  那人不肯說
I asked. Guy wouldn't tell me.
不過不管是什么活  酬勞很可觀
But whatever it is, it's serious money.
而且那人
And the guy...
指名要你
he specifically asked for you.
那人是誰
And who's the guy?
我控制不住了  長官
I can't hold it, sir.
失控了  上校
No control on the planes, Captain.
我們正在快速下沉
We're going down and fast.
"我們正在快速下沉"
"We're going down and fast."
快看
Check this out.
這地方很精彩
This is a good part.
他們最后全死光了嗎  告訴我這個就行
So, do they all die? Tell me that much.
洛克·哈德森帶他們撞冰山了嗎
Does Rock Hudson run 'em into an iceberg?
他先拍的這個還是《麥克米蘭夫婦》
Is this...before or after he did "McMillan & Wife"?
別說話  好好看
Shut up. Watch the movie.
你怎么會有這么奇怪的愛好
What is this weird fascination you have
喜歡看人被困在北極
with stories of men trapped on the North Pole?
《大北極》的設定在北極
"Ice Station Zebra" is on the North Pole.
《怪形》發生在南極
"The Thing" takes place on the South Pole.
這兩個天差地別
They literally could not be any more different.
我爸特喜歡這個
My dad loves this one.
是啊  他和霍華德·休斯都愛看
Yeah, him and Howard Hughes.
是啊
I know, right?
都對這片子贊不絕口
Can't get two finer reviews than that.
空氣瓶組內還剩多少壓力
How much pressure's left in the air banks?
不足八百磅  長官
Down 800 pounds, sir.
是老板
It's the boss.
這時候打電話來
At this hour?
是啊
Yeah.
祝賀嘛  多晚都不嫌遲
It's never too late for congratulations.
克利福徳  天哪  這個點了你還在辦公室
Cliff, Jesus, you're still at the office?
你播了一支廣告
You ran a commercial?
是啊  天哪
Yeah, and, oh, my God,
我跟你說  那反響簡直
let me tell you, the response has been --
你拍了一個廣告  沒給我過目就播出去了
You ran a commercial without ever showing it to me,
也沒有事先征求我和合伙人的意見
without first consulting me and my partners.
你真以為我會同意嗎
Did you actually think that was gonna fly?!
我打算明天早上告訴你的
I was planning on telling you in the morning.
廣告播出一天之后才告訴我
The day after it aired?!
只播出了一次  只面向很小一部分觀眾
I only ran it once, just in one small market.
只是個試驗而已  好吧
It was kind of an experiment, all right?
沒什么人注意
Kind of under the radar.
而且公平地講
And in all fairness,
你說過的  客戶聯系這塊歸我管
you did tell me client outreach was my department.
不要狡辯了
Don't be disingenuous.
這個廣告提到我的公司名了吧
This commercial -- I take it my firm's name is mentioned?
是的  提到了
Yes. Yeah.
天哪
Jesus...
霍華德說你有些古怪
Howard said you were a little eccentric.
他可沒說你這么能惹事兒
He didn't tell me you were a goddamn arsonist!
克利福德  說真的  我不認為
Cliff, to be fair, I don't think, uh...
如果是我誤解了你的話
I apologize if there was any misreading
我道歉
of the situation on my part,
但是現在形勢大好
but there's a very positive headline here.
我們今天接到了103個電話
We got 103 phone calls today,
區區七百塊廣告費就有這么好的效果
off a measly $700 ad buy.
這種投資回報率可不是你...
Now that kind of return on investment you can't g--
明早八點  到我辦公室來  合伙人也在
Tomorrow morning, 8:00, my office, with the partners,
把你拍的那玩意兒也帶來
and we want to see this thing.
克利福德  等你看到這廣告  你肯定
Cliff, when you see this, I know you'll --
好的  克利福德
Yeah, Cliff.
謝謝
Thank you.
你也是
Yeah, you, too.
好的
Okay.
再見
See ya.
成功男人啊
Golden boy.
說的就是我
That's me.
我錯過什么了
So, what'd I miss?
炸了沒
Anything blow up yet?
覺得該小心行事了
Feeling cautious?
說吧  你把我叫來這里什么事
You gonna tell me what we're doing here?
我遇到麻煩了
I've got a problem.
-然后呢  -這個麻煩
- Okay. - This problem...
我自己解決不了
I can't solve it myself.
這個麻煩  是人還是事
This problem -- is it a who or a what?
有個人
There's a guy.
我想要他消失
I need him to go away.
非常歡迎愛好者加入字幕組一起翻譯海外影視劇